Glee Club Records UA170
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Glee Club Records
1889 -- 1951
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts College Glee Club
UA170
4.66 Linear Feet 4 boxes
9 Digital Object(s)
201.87 Megabytes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series: Glee Club and Unprocessed Accesssions.
Custodial History
This collection was formed from items found in the stacks and scrapbooks that were formally part of the memory books collection (MS075).
Biographical / Historical
The first Tufts College Glee Club was formed in 1863, but the club was inconsistently organized until 1885, when the permanent Glee Club was formed. Its first concert was held on March 15, 1886. Leo R. Lewis, A'87, was the organizer and founder of the permanent club in 1885 and went on to serve on the Tufts faculty from 1892-1945. He was the conductor and leader of the Glee Club throughout his tenure on the faculty. Elbridge Newton, A'90, wrote "The Brown and Blue," the first Tufts song, for the club in 1888. The club published the Tufts Song Book in 1895 and in 1906.
The Glee Club was all male from its founding. An all-female Glee Club, the Tufts Girls Glee Club, was formed at Jackson College in 1906. The two clubs performed separately until 1928, when they began to have occasional concerts together. They formally merged in World War II to create a Combined Tufts and Jackson Glee Club.
The Glee Club disbanded after the 1948-1949 academic year.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains scrapbooks, photographs, and songs related to the Tufts College Glee Club.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Student life; Glee Club; Student Activities -- Student Government, Clubs, and Organizations; Student Activities -- Performing Arts
- Glee Club, 1889 -- 1930; UA170.001; 2.2 Linear Feet; 9 Digital Object(s); 201.87 Megabytes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains scrapbooks and photographs related to the Tufts College Glee Club.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as found.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Tufts College Glee Club, scrapbook, 1889 -- 1930; UA170.001.001 (Box 1)
    Box 1 of 2.
  - Tufts College Glee Club, scrapbook, 1889 -- 1930; UA170.001.002 (Box 2)
    Box 2 of 2.
  - The Jumbonians, Tufts College, 1926 -- 1927; UA170.001.003.00001 (Box Shared 127)
    Photograph identifies members on the back. Back row left to right: Godfrey?, S.A. Nevens, R.S. Fellows, B.L. Paige, N.B. Baker, E.B. Christensen, J.S. Stevens, Jr., J.R. Yarrow, J.B. Poore, C.B. Rheiner, Lincoln?, Ross? 3rd row left to right: Esner?, E. Kimfall, H.S. Evans, J.E. Lovewell, C.E. Smith, Lovewell?, R. Loveland, H.F. Tomfolorde, Jr., G.B. Chisholm, A.A. Thibodeau, L.W. Abbott, D.H. Mitchell 2nd row left to right: M.E. Gallagher, Jr., Withers?, D.T. Chase, Jr., D.D. Moats, N.M. Biller, C.S. Ford, G.P. Nye, L.M. Munro, T.H. Serger, W.N. Davis, Shroader? Front row left to right: M.E. Loberon, W.A. Parkbunt, F. L. Archibald, J. Sauders, F.J. Sauders, J.F. Reilly, F.M. Fellows, C.H. Young, M.F. Tigs, H.B. Swimdells, J.A. Thompson Seated left to right: V.H. Meyer, M. Tarlow, J.T. Drisdrau, P.S. Seller
    Spellings are approximate.
    photographic print
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1915 -- 1917; UA170.001.003.00002 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1915 -- 1920; UA170.001.003.00003 (Box Shared 127)
    This photograph was found uncatalogued in the summer of 2008.
  - Tufts College Glee Club, season of 1889-1890, UA170.001.003.00004 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Banjo Club, season of 1889-1890, UA170.001.003.00005 (Box Shared 127)
    According to "A History of Music in Tufts College 1856-1945," it was indicated the the Banjo Club was essentially the Glee Club before the Glee Club was an official name for all musical groups.
  - Tufts College Glee and Banjo Club, season of 1890-1891, UA170.001.003.00006 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, season of 1891-1892, UA170.001.003.00007 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1892 -- 1893; UA170.001.003.00008 (Box Shared 127)
    Inscription on photograph: "presented by Charles Dow Clark, Tufts '95."
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1896 -- 1897; UA170.001.003.00009 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1897 -- 1898; UA170.001.003.00010 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1898 -- 1899; UA170.001.003.00011 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1899 -- 1900; UA170.001.003.00012 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1901 -- 1902; UA170.001.003.00013 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1902 -- 1903; UA170.001.003.00014 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1905 -- 1906; UA170.001.003.00015 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1906 -- 1907; UA170.001.003.00016 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1907 -- 1908; UA170.001.003.00017 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1908 -- 1909; UA170.001.003.00018 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1909 -- 1910; UA170.001.003.00019 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1910 -- 1911; UA170.001.003.00020 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts College Glee and Mandolin Club, 1911 -- 1912; UA170.001.003.00021 (Box Shared 127)
  - Tufts Glee Club, 1912 -- 1913; UA170.001.003.00022 (Box Shared 127)
  - Glee Club, Regular Members, 1916-1917, UA170.001.003.00023 (Box Shared 127)
  - Glee Club, February-June 1919, UA170.001.003.00024 (Box Shared 127)
  - Glee Club, 1919-1920, UA170.001.003.00025 (Box Shared 127)
  - Glee Club, 1921 -- 1922; UA170.001.003.00026 (Box Shared 127)
  - Glee Club, 1922 -- 1923; UA170.001.003.00027 (Box Shared 127)
  - Bolton Forrest Herbert letter to Florence Field, 1905-12-17; UA170.001.004.00001; Herbert, Bolton Forrest (Box 4)
    Bolton Forrest Herbert wrote this letter as a freshman at Tufts College. He was a member of the Glee Club, and in this letter he recounts student hazing and a speech given at Tufts by Booker T. Washington on the "Negro question". The Glee Club performed at the Washington event.
    Correspondence; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915
  - Tufts Glee Club and Odikon Singers Songs, 1913 -- 1951; UA170.00001; 8 Digital Object(s); 201.87 Megabytes
    This digital object contains 8 songs from a CD. Tufts Glee Club (1913): 1. For Tufts, Hurrah! 2. Brown and Blue; Odikon Singers (1951): 3. Dear Alma Mater 4. Brown and Blue 5. Jumbo Victory March 6. Spell it Out for Tufts 7. Tuftonia's Day 8. Te Salutamus
    - For Tufts, Hurrah!, 1913; UA170.000035; 1 Digital Object(s); 27.05 Megabytes
    - Brown and Blue; Odikon Singers, 1951; UA170.000036; 1 Digital Object(s); 25.37 Megabytes
    - Dear Alma Mater, 1913; UA170.000037; 1 Digital Object(s); 28.3 Megabytes
    - Brown and Blue, 1913; UA170.000038; 1 Digital Object(s); 21.42 Megabytes
    - Jumbo Victory March, 1913; UA170.000039; 1 Digital Object(s); 14.18 Megabytes
    - Spell it Out for Tufts, 1913; UA170.000040; 1 Digital Object(s); 25.14 Megabytes
    - Tuftonia's Day, 1913; UA170.000041; 1 Digital Object(s); 27.8 Megabytes
    - Te Salutamus, 1913; UA170.000042; 1 Digital Object(s); 32.61 Megabytes